A Register of the Albert J. and Roberta Wohlstetter Papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- Speeches and Writings, 1936-1996. (Box 62)
  - Roberta Wohlstetter File, 1933-1996.
    - "Aftershocks in Japan: Balancing the Bomb and Other Explosives," paper, California Arms Control and Foreign Policy Seminar, California, 1973 September
      - Background materials (Folder 79: 3)
      - Notes and typescript (Folder 79: 4)
    - "Alternatives to Mass Destruction as Deterrent: Comments on the Addresses of Professor York and Mr. Clifford," paper, Pacem in Terris III conference, Center for the Study of Democratic Institutions, Santa Barbara, California, 1973 October 9
      - General (Folder 79: 5)
      - Correspondence (Folder 79: 6)
      - Notes (Folder 79: 7)
      - Typescript. (Folder 79: 8)
        Includes printed copy of comments on Clark Clifford's paper
    - Participation, Mutual Force Reduction in Europe and the Northern Flank, California Arms Control and Foreign Policy Seminar, California, 1973 December 13
      - General (Folder 79: 9)
      - Notes (Folder 79: 10)
    - Participation, Finland's Defence Policy, California Arms Control and Foreign Policy Seminar, University of California, Los Angeles, 1974 February 13-15 (Box 80)
      - General (Folder 80: 1)
      - Background materials (Folder 80: 2)
      - Correspondence (Folder 80: 3)
      - Notes (Folder 80: 4)
    - Remarks, Expert Advice and Public Choice conference, Center for the Policy Study, sponsored by the University of Chicago in cooperation with the Johnson Foundation, Racine, Wisconsin, 1974 April 4-6
      - General (Folder 80: 5-6)
      - Correspondence (Folder 80: 7)
      - Notes (Folder 80: 8)
      - Typescript (Folder 80: 9)
    - "Legends of the Strategic Arms Race: The Driving Engine," paper, Conference on Arms Competition and Strategic Doctrine, California Arms Control and Foreign Policy Seminar, California, 1974 June 5-6 (Box 81)
      - General (Folder 81: 1)
      - Background materials (Folder 81: 2)
      - Correspondence (Folder 81: 3)
      - Notes (Folder 81: 4)
      - Typescript (Folder 81: 5-6)
    - "Legends of the Strategic Arms Race: The Driving Engine," paper, Arms Control Workshop, Aspen, Colorado, 1974 August 5-16
      - General (Folder 81: 7)
      - Background materials (Folder 81: 8)
      - Notes (Box-folder 82: 1)
      - Typescript (Folder 82: 2)
      - Printed copy. Strategic Review, 1974 Fall (Folder 82: 3)
    - "Political Military Concepts and Technical Strategic Realities," and "Future Options and Technologies of Discrimination," remarks, Advanced Research Project Agency (ARPA) Workshop, 1974 October 1-2
      - General (Folder 82: 4)
      - Background materials (Folder 82: 5)
      - Correspondence (Folder 82: 6)
      - Notes and typescript outline (Folder 82: 7)
    - Participation, International Security Affairs Symposium, National War College, Fort McNair, Washington, D.C., 1974 November 1-2
      - General (Folder 82: 8)
      - Correspondence (Folder 82: 9)
      - Notes (Folder 82: 10)
    - Participation, The Future of U.S. Alliance Relations conference, sponsored by the California Arms Control and Foreign Policy Seminar, Palm Springs, California, 1975 January 5-8
      - General (Folder 82: 11)
      - Correspondence (Folder 82: 12)
      - Notes (Folder 82: 13)
    - Discussion remarks, seminar, Los Angeles, California, 1975 October 4. (Folder 82: 14)
    - Remarks, U.S. Nuclear Policy and International Security panel, Working Group on U.S. National Aims, International Agreements and Strategic Forces, California Seminar on Arms Control and Foreign Policy, California, 1976 December 7 (Box 83)
      - Background materials (Folder 83: 1)
      - Typescript (Folder 83: 2)
    - Participation, symposium on Iran, Stanford Research Institute, SRI-Washington, Washington, D.C., 1977 October 4-6
      - General (Folder 83: 3)
      - Correspondence (Folder 83: 4)
      - Typewritten transcript of conference notes (Folder 83: 5)
    - Opening statement, New Alternatives Workshop, Chicago, Illinois, 1977 October 19-20
      - General (Folder 83: 6)
      - Correspondence (Folder 83: 7)
      - Notes (Folder 83: 8)
      - Outline (Folder 83: 9)
    - Participation, Defense Implications of Nuclear Weapons Proliferation Conference, Defense Nuclear Agency, 1978 December 14
      - General (Folder 83: 10)
      - Notes (Folder 83: 11)
    - Participation, DNA New Alternatives Workshop, Science Applications, Inc., La Jolla, California, 1979 March 15-16
      - General (Folder 83: 12)
      - Correspondence (Folder 83: 13)
      - Notes (Folder 83: 14)
    - Participation, DNA New Alternatives Workshop, SRI International, Menlo Park, California, 1979 June 21-22
      - General (Folder 83: 15)
      - Correspondence (Folder 83: 16)
      - Notes (Folder 83: 17)
    - Participation, defense expansion conference, Hoover Institution, Stanford University, California, 1980 February 26
      - General (Folder 83: 18)
      - Background materials (Folder 83: 19)
      - Correspondence (Folder 83: 20)
      - Notes (Folder 83: 21)
    - "The Turkish-U.S. Alliance and Geopolitical Change since World War II," paper, Turkey and the West conference, City University, New York, 1980 March 20-21 (Box 84)
      - General (Folder 84: 1)
      - Background materials (Folder 84: 2)
      - Notes (Folder 84: 3)
      - Typescript (Folder 84: 4)
    - Discussion remarks, The Soviet Challenge: Potential Crises in the Persian Gulf and East Asia, Security Conference on Asia and the Pacific (SECAP), Elkridge, Maryland, 1980 June 19-20
      - General (Folder 84: 5)
      - Correspondence (Folder 84: 6)
      - Notes (Folder 84: 7)
      - Typescript (Folder 84: 8)
    - Participation, IFRI seminar, Paris, 1980 June 24. (Folder 84: 9)
      Participant list
    - Remarks, Middle East – Turkey and NATO, symposium, Turkish Atlantic Treaty Association, Istanbul, Turkey, 1980 July 4-6
      - General (Folder 84: 10)
      - Background materials (Folder 84: 11)
      - Notes (Folder 84: 12)
      - Outline (Folder 84: 13)
    - Participation, International Atomic Energy conference, Vienna, Austria, 1980 July 10. (Folder 84: 14)
    - Remarks, Wolfsberg Conference, 1980 September 15-17
      - General (Folder 84: 15)
      - Background materials (Folder 84: 16)
      - Outlines (Folder 84: 17)
    - Participation, The Persian Gulf and the Western Economies, Security Conference on Asia and the Pacific (SECAP), Tokyo, Japan, 1981 January 23-25 (Box 85)
      - General (Folder 85: 1)
      - Background materials (Folder 85: 2)
      - Notes (Folder 85: 3)
    - Paper, The Impact of Worldwide Or Widely Separated Challenges on the Free World's Defense Capabilities, DNA New Alternatives Workshop, Industrial College of the Armed Forces, Fort McNair, Washington, D.C., 1981 February 4-5
      - General (Folder 85: 4)
      - Background materials (Folder 85: 5)
      - Correspondence (Folder 85: 6)
      - Notes (Folder 85: 7)
      - Typescript (Folder 85: 8)
    - "Coping with Lethal Threats in Many Theaters: Toward a Coherent Strategy on National Security," presentation, Hoover Institution seminar, Stanford University, California, 1981 April 2-3
      - General (Folder 85: 9)
      - Notes (Folder 85: 10)
    - Participation, America's Security in the 1980s, Twenty-Third Annual Conference, International Institute for Strategic Studies, Williamsburg, Virginia, 1981 September 10-13
      - General (Folder 85: 11)
      - Notes (Folder 85: 12)
    - Remarks, Challenges to Security in East Asia, Security Conference On Asia and the Pacific (SECAP), Palm Springs, California, 1982 January 8-10
      - General (Folder 85: 13)
      - Outline (Folder 85: 14)
    - "Responding to Ambiguous Warning: Overview of Issues," remarks, New Alternatives Workshop, 1982 April 20-21
      - General (Folder 85: 15)
      - Background materials (Folder 85: 16)
      - Correspondence (Folder 85: 17)
      - Notes and outline (Folder 85: 18)
    - "Deciding to Respond to Ambiguous Signs of Trouble in the Third World," paper, DIA I and W Seminar, 1982 May 18. (Folder 85: 19)
      Outline and typescript summary
    - Comments, Palm Springs Workshop? Palm Springs, California?, 1982 July 9. (Folder 85: 20)
    - Discussion remarks, East-West Credit and Alliance Strategy, panel on Poland, California Seminar on International Security and Foreign Policy, California, 1982 July 20
      - General (Folder 85: 21)
      - Typescript (Folder 85: 22)
    - "NATO and Turkey after the Détente," paper, SISAV Conference on NATO in the 80s, Istanbul, Turkey, 1982 October
      - General (Folder 85: 23)
      - Background materials (Folder 85: 24)
      - Notes (Folder 85: 25)
      - Typescript. (Box-folder 86: 1-3)
        Includes another version entitled, "NATO after the Détente," and proceedings
      - Printed copy (Folder 86: 4)
    - "Strategy, Technology and the Threat," remarks, DNA New Alternatives Workshop on New Strategies, New Technologies and the Changing Threat, San Francisco, California, 1982 November 22-23
      - General (Folder 86: 5)
      - Background materials (Folder 86: 6)
      - Correspondence (Folder 86: 7)
      - Notes (Folder 86: 8)
      - Outline (Folder 86: 9)
      - Typescript. (Folder 86: 10)
        Includes a paper entitled "The Soviet Threat," 1982 December 3
      - Typescript (Box-folder 87: 1)
    - Participation, Latin America conference, 1983 February 3-16. (Folder 87: 2)
    - Participation, Reducing Nuclear Threats workshop, Los Angeles, California, 1983 February 23-26
      - General (Folder 87: 3)
      - Notes (Folder 87: 4)
    - Remarks, The Nuclear Balance of Power, United States Information Agency conference, Los Angeles, California, 1983 April 6
      - Background materials (Folder 87: 5)
      - Correspondence (Folder 87: 6)
      - Notes and typescript briefings with Fred Hoffman and James Digby (Folder 87: 7)
    - Remarks, Security Conference on Asia and the Pacific (SECAP), planning session, Honolulu, Hawaii, 1983 June 9-10
      - General (Folder 87: 8)
      - Background materials (Folder 87: 9)
      - Notes (Folder 87: 10)
    - Participation, Trans-Atlantic Conference on East-West Trade, Stanford University, California, 1983 August 25-26
      - General (Folder 87: 11)
      - Background materials (Folder 87: 12)
      - Notes (Folder 87: 13)
    - Comments, DNA New Alternatives Workshop, Arlington, Virginia, 1983 October 24-25
      - General (Folder 87: 14)
      - Background materials (Folder 87: 15)
      - Correspondence (Folder 87: 16)
      - Notes (Folder 87: 17)
      - Typescript (Folder 87: 18)
    - "Armenian Terror as a Special Case on International Terror" (with Nancy Virts), paper, International Terrorism symposium, Ankara University, Ankara, Turkey, 1984 April 17-18 (Box 88)
      - Background materials (Folder 88: 1)
      - Notes and typescript (Folder 88: 2)
    - Comments on Michael May, "Possible Climatic Effects of Nuclear War," California Seminar on International Security and Foreign Policy, 1984 April 20
      - General (Folder 88: 3)
      - Typescript (Folder 88: 4)
    - Participation, A Strategic Assessment of New Offense and Defense Technologies, DNA New Alternatives Workshop, Arlington, Virginia, 1984 April 24-26
      - General (Folder 88: 5)
      - Background materials (Folder 88: 6)
      - Notes (Folder 88: 7)
    - Participation, New Technology and Western Security Policy, Twenty-Sixth Annual Conference, International Institute for Strategic Studies, Avignon, France, 1984 September 13-16
      - General (Folder 88: 8)
      - Notes (Folder 88: 9)
    - Participation, U.S.-Turkish Views of the Middle East, conference co-sponsored by the Heritage Foundation and the Foreign Policy Institute (Ankara), Washington, D.C., 1984 October 4
      - General (Folder 88: 10)
      - Notes (Folder 88: 11)
    - "Turkey and the Defense of Western Interests," paper, Council on Foreign Relations, 1984 November 12
      - General (Folder 88: 12)
      - Background materials (Folder 88: 13)
      - Notes (Folder 88: 14)
      - Typescript (Folder 88: 15)
    - "Increasing Foreign Policy Choices Beyond 'Better Red than Dead'," remarks, and keynote address, American Foreign Policy: Reassertiveness or Retrenchment? Implications for the Future, Thirty-Sixth Annual Student Conference on United States Affairs, United States Military Academy, West Point, New York, 1984 November 14-17
      - Outline and typescript (Folder 88: 16)
      - Printed copy (Folder 88: 17)
    - "The Future of SDI?" paper, DNA New Alternatives Workshop, Ft. Belvoir, Virginia, 1984 November 20-21
      - General (Folder 88: 18)
      - Outline and typescript (Folder 88: 19)
    - Remarks, New Alternatives Workshop, Presidio, San Francisco, California, 1985 June 20-21
      - General (Folder 88: 20)
      - Background materials (Folder 88: 21)
      - Correspondence (Folder 88: 22)
      - Notes (Folder 88: 23)
      - Outline (Folder 88: 24)
    - "How Has the United States Met Its Major Challenges Since 1945?" remarks, symposium, 1985 November? (Box 89)
      - General (Folder 89: 1)
      - Correspondence (Folder 89: 2)
      - Printed copy. Commentary, 1985 November (Folder 89: 3)
    - Paper, New Technologies and the Political and Military Control of Conflict, DNA New Alternatives Workshop, Arlington Hall Station, Virginia, 1985 November 20-21
      - General (Folder 89: 4)
      - Background materials (Folder 89: 5)
      - Correspondence (Folder 89: 6)
      - Notes (Folder 89: 7)
      - Typescript (Folder 89: 8)
      - Revised typescript, 1986 February 12 (Folder 89: 9)
    - Remarks, DNA New Alternatives Workshop, Science Applications International Corporation, Falls Church, Virginia, 1986 June 25-26
      - General (Folder 89: 10)
      - Background materials (Folder 89: 11)
      - Correspondence (Folder 89: 12)
      - Notes (Folder 89: 13)
    - Presentation, BMD LRRD II, DNA New Alternatives Workshop, the DNA Long-Range R&D II Program, Arlington, Virginia, 1988 April 27-28
      - General (Folder 89: 14)
      - Background materials (Folder 89: 15)
      - Correspondence (Folder 89: 16)
      - Notes (Box-folder 90: 1)
      - Outline and typescript (Folder 90: 2)
    - Participation, American and Japanese World Perspectives: A Period of Transition, Security Conference on Asia and the Pacific (SECAP), Los Angeles, California, 1989 February 3-5
      - General (Folder 90: 3)
      - Background materials (Folder 90: 4)
      - Notes (Folder 90: 5)
    - Speech, Bishops Statesman conference, Olin Center, Chicago, 1989 June 8. (Folder 90: 6)
    - "Japanese and U.S. Objectives for Trade and Economic Growth Which Would be Incompatible and Those That Might Actually Help Each Other," remarks, The Rise and Fall of the U.S. in the Changing World of Military and Economic Competition? California Seminar on International Security and Foreign Policy, 1990 January 30
      - Background materials. (Folder 90: 7)
        Includes a letter from James Digby
      - Outline and typescript (Folder 90: 8)
    - "Has the Economic Threat From Japan Replaced the Soviet Military Threat? Notes on R&D and Some Differences between All-Out Nuclear War and Foreign Trade" (with Nancy Virts), presentation, RGS Seminar, 1990 February 13
      - Notes (Folder 90: 9)
      - Outline and typescript (Folder 90: 10)
    - "Economic and Security Policy in a Period of Drastic Change," paper, Security Conference on Asia and the Pacific (SECAP), Oiso, Japan, 1990 April 6-8
      - General (Folder 90: 11-12)
      - Background materials (Box-folder 91: 1)
      - Correspondence (Folder 91: 2)
      - Notes. (Folder 91: 3)
        Includes notes entitled "Genocide by Mediation," and "Markets, Democracy and Nationalities in the Soviet Empire"
      - Typescript. (Folder 91: 4-5)
        Includes other typescript papers entitled "Economic and Security Policy in a Revolutionary Time," and "Towards a Coherent Framework for Cooperation"
    - Participation, Central Europe on the Way to Democracy conference, Vienna, Austria, 1990 June 28-July 1 (Box 92)
      - General (Folder 92: 1)
      - Correspondence (Folder 92: 2)
      - Notes (Folder 92: 3)
    - "The Fax Shall Make You Free," paper, Peaceful Road to Democracy Conference, Prague, Czech Republic, 1990 July 4-6
      - General (Folder 92: 4)
      - Background materials (Folder 92: 5)
      - Correspondence (Folder 92: 6)
      - Notes (Folder 92: 7)
      - Outline (Folder 92: 8)
      - Typescript. (Folder 92: 9)
        Includes revised version, 1990 August 21 and December 3
      - Translation into French (Folder 92: 10)
    - Participation, Supporting East European Democracy and Free Markets conference, Rand Corporation, Santa Monica, California, 1990 September 21-22
      - General (Folder 92: 11)
      - Background materials (Folder 92: 12)
      - Notes (Folder 92: 13)
    - Participation, Kuwaiti Perspective seminar, University of California, Los Angeles, California, 1990 December 5. (Box-folder 93: 1)
    - "National Economic Security," paper, Economic Dimensions of National Security conference, Rand Corporation, Santa Monica, California, 1992 February 7-8
      - General (Folder 93: 2)
      - Background materials (Folder 93: 3)
      - Notes (Folder 93: 4)
      - Typescript (Folder 93: 5)
    - "Place of Okinawa: Return of Administrative Rights and U.S. Bases," paper, Commemorative Events of the Twentieth Anniversary of the Reversion of Okinawa Symposium, Tokyo, Japan, 1992 May 13-16
      - General (Folder 93: 6-7)
      - Background materials (Folder 93: 8)
      - Correspondence (Folder 93: 9)
      - Notes (Folder 93: 10)
      - Typescript. (Folder 93: 11)
        Includes typewritten response by Wohlstetter entitled, "Answer to Questionnaire on My Role in the Process of the Reversion of Okinawa"
    - "Bosnia As Future," paper, seminar on Lessons from Bosnia, Rand Corporation, Santa Monica, California, 1993 August 5
      - Typescript. (Folder 93: 12)
      - Translation into German (Folder 93: 13)
    - Participation, Political and Strategic Lessons from Western Policies Towards the Conflicts in Croatia and Bosnia workshop, Forschungsinstitut für Internationale Politik und Sicherheit, Stiftung Wissenschaft und Politik, Ebenhausen, Germany, 1994 February 3-4 (Box 94)
      - General (Folder 94: 1)
      - Correspondence (Folder 94: 2)
      - Notes (Folder 94: 3)
    - "Flaws in the North Korean Accord and in the NPT: Implications for US Policy and the NPT Review," paper, Aspen Strategy Group Conference, US Policy after the Korean Nuclear Agreement, Maryland, 1995 March 10-11
      - General (Folder 94: 4)
      - Background materials (Folder 94: 5)
      - Correspondence (Folder 94: 6)
      - Typescript (Folder 94: 7)
    - "Alternatives to Negotiating Genocide," paper, International Conference on Bosnia-Herzegovina, Bilkent University, Ankara, Turkey, 1995 April 17-19
      - General (Folder 94: 8)
      - Background materials (Folder 94: 9)
      - Correspondence (Folder 94: 10)
      - Typescript (Folder 94: 11)
    - Participation, After Dayton: Prospects For Peace in the Balkans, Balkan Policy Review Conference, Balkan Institute, Washington, D.C., 1996 April 12. (Folder 94: 12)
      Printed copy
  - Conversation transcripts., See Speeches and Writings/ Speeches
  - Interviews.
    Includes oral histories
    - By Albert Wohlstetter
      - General. (Folder 94: 13)
      - Ted Draper about Cuba, 1963 May 17. (Folder 94: 14)
        Typescript summary
      - Carlos Garcia, 1964 October 1. (Folder 94: 15)
      - Douglas Pike (with Roberta Wohlstetter), 1966 March 17. (Folder 94: 16)
      - Cuban interviewees, 1967 April.; See also Roberta Wohlstetter File (Folder 94: 17)
        Notebooks.
      - Helmut Schmidt, 1980 February. (Folder 94: 18)
    - Of Albert Wohlstetter
      - Richard T. Cooper, on the ABM debate, 1967 February 19, Chicago Sunday Sun-Times. (Folder 94: 19)
      - "The Potential Effect of Crisis Relocation on Crisis Stability,", 1978 April 18. (Folder 94: 20)
      - Development of Strategic Thinking at the Rand Corporation, 1948-1963: A Mathematical Logician's View,", 1985 July 5. (Folder 94: 21)
        Typewritten transcript
      - Martin J. Collins and Dr. Joseph Tatarewicz, National Air and Space Museum and Rand Corporation, Joint Oral History Project on the History of the Rand Corporation, Rand Corporation, Santa Monica, California, 1987 July 29 (Box 95)
        - General (Folder 95: 1)
        - Correspondence (Folder 95: 2)
        - Typewritten transcript (Folder 95: 3)
      - Amal Mudallali, on the Soviet threat in the Gulf, Riyadh Daily, 1988 January 28. (Folder 95: 4)
      - Allen Greb and James Digby, "The Strategist Reflects on the Past and Future of Nuclear Policies,", 1990 August 2
        - Background materials (Folder 95: 5)
        - Correspondence (Folder 95: 6)
        - Typewritten transcript (Folder 95: 7)
      - Joseph Fitchett, "A Step-by-Step Strategy: Iraqi Radars Suggested as Target," International Herald Tribune, 1991 January 14. (Folder 95: 8)
      - Daniel Reed, British Broadcasting Corporation, on the role of mathematics in the work of the Rand Corporation, 1991 October?
        - Background materials (Folder 95: 9)
        - Correspondence (Folder 95: 10)
      - Erika Benes, on the Balkans, Voice of America, 1994 May 5. (Folder 95: 11)
        Notes and typewritten transcript
  - Letters to the editor
    - On the ABM debate, Phalanx, n.d. (Folder 95: 12)
    - On Hugh Thomas' article on Theodore Draper's book, New York Times, n.d. (Folder 95: 13)
    - "Scientists, Seers and Strategy," New York Times, 1963 April 11. (Folder 95: 14)
      Printed copy.
    - On David Lilienthal's article entitled "Scientific Experts," New York Times, 1963 October-November. (Folder 95: 15)
      Typescript and related materials
    - On Marcus Raskin's review of the article by Robert Levine entitled "The Arms Debate," New York Review of Books, 1963 December. (Folder 95: 16)
    - "Challenges Lowe," Navy, 1964 March. (Folder 95: 17)
    - On Rathjens's letter on the Minuteman, New York Times, 1969 June-July. (Folder 95: 18)
    - On Jack Ruina's letter to the Washington Post re the ABM debate, 1971 October-November. (Folder 95: 19)
      Typescript and related materials prepared by Albert Wohlstetter for the response of the Operations Research Society of America (ORSA)
    - On the ABM debate, Washington Post, 1971 December 15. (Folder 95: 20)
    - On Joseph Kraft's column, Washington Post, 1977 January. (Folder 95: 21)
      Typescript, printed copy, and related materials
    - "Nuclear Temptations: An Exchange," New York Review, 1984 May 31. (Folder 95: 22)
    - On Solly Zuckerman's review of Gregg Herken's book, New York Review of Books, 1985 September 9. (Box-folder 96: 1)
    - On exchange rates, Wall Street Journal, 1989 November 6. (Folder 96: 2)
    - "The Case for Destroying Saddam's Army," Wall Street Journal, 1991 January 15. (Folder 96: 3)
    - "Aims of Desert Storm and After," Wall Street Journal, 1991 January 25. (Folder 96: 4)
      Notes and printed copy
    - "Cheers, Raspberries, and the Dream" (with Fred Hoffman), Los Angeles Times, 1991 March 17. (Folder 96: 5)
    - "Programmed to Self-Destruct," Wall Street Journal, 1993 August 25. (Folder 96: 6)
  - Newspaper articles
    - General
      - General
        - General (Folder 96: 7-10)
        - Responses from readers
          - Undated (Folder 96: 11)
          - 1992-1994 (Folder 96: 12)
      - Saturday Evening Post. Notes, typescripts, and related materials (Folder 96: 13)
      - Wall Street Journal. (Folder 96: 14)
        Includes Albert Wohlstetter's correspondence with Wall Street Journal Europe regarding various drafts and their publication